welcome to episode number 297 of
de numero res grata CCXCVII
category 5 technology TV it's Tuesday
V genus technology TV suus 'Martis
the 28th of May 28 though it may
28 mensis Maii XXVIII etiamsi multis
thirteen hey gang are you doing I'm
heus Im 'tredecim cohors agis
Robbie Ferguson your host and I'm Eric
Robbie Tacitus exercitum tuum, et non sum Eric
Kidd and you know what I'm gonna tell
Kidd et Im 'agnus dei scitis quod dico
you what's coming up in the newsroom
quid suus 'vestri venit in newsroom
right now right now next thing you know
iam iam tu scis altera est
your fantasy football team will be
fantasy eu quadrigis vestri erunt
coming to Linux whoo and biting their
Linux venit ad whoo et mordentes
thumb at all those who said QR codes are
QR code sunt omnes qui pollicis
dead mercedes-benz has found a way to
Mercedes-Benz in via, et inventus est mortuus
use QR codes to save lives do you know
QR code salute uti nosti
your facebook friends do you know who
facebook amici tui qui te nesciunt
they are because they might be a
quoniam ipsi essent
criminal gang out to kidnap you
criminalibus cohors rapere de vobis
seriously an 18 year old student yes has
XVIII quod anno quod sic habet vetus gravissime discipulus
built a device that charges a dead cell
extruxit cellam defunctum reperit pessimas
phone in only 20 seconds you should
In phone tantum XX minutes vos should
stick around these stories are coming up
talia ascenderunt perstiteris
later in the show boy oh boy that'd be
vellem autem esse apud post spectaculum puer o pueri
spectacular which part 1 and then
et quod spectaculi pars I
kidnapped or the or the phone that was
et tollebant vel telephonum id est
charged my second in 20 seconds yeah my
secundo, præcepit mihi in me yeah XX seconds
hi I'll call you back in 20 seconds the
Et beatos vos a hi rursus in XX seconds
phone's dying yeah okay I'm back oh if
O si me tergum bene moriendi scriptor phone yeah
only I could charge me up that quickly
possit arguere me solum quia ego cito
when that'd be awesome hey on tonight's
illa youd 'heus in nocte cum terribilis sis scriptor
show we're gonna be having some fun
ostende nobis sit amet aliquam habens fun
we're gonna be taking the old are you no
erant 'non agnus dei esse taking the illi,
fun at all sorry I didn't realize that
omnino scire non paenitet amet
there was a rule no fun tonight the new
nec erat regula hac nocte fun novum
a new that's also known as the
Et nota, quod suus 'sicut novum
wildebeest to new the GNU image
wildebeest ad imaginem novi GNU
manipulation program the GIMP is a free
manipulation programma est libera ad GIMP
graphic editing software al a kind of
graphic software emendo quaedam al
like Photoshop or something like that
aut sicut aliquid, quod quasi Photoshop
but we are going to show you tonight how
sed nos ad te nocte ut ostenderet
to add digital depth of field to your
digital addere profundum agro tuo
photos to make them kind of pop out of
quaedam imaginibus facere pop
the screen pop out of your prints you're
ad pop de screen vestigia tua tibi
gonna love it let's stick around don't
suus 'agnus dei amore lets' inhaero circum ne
go anywhere we'll be right back this is
Haec est ius eundi erimus
category 5 technology TV
V genus technology TV
at eco alkalines we believe you should
Eco alkalines ad vos, ut credimus,
be able to trust your batteries not just
posse confidunt tua eu gravida, non solum
here but here here and here but with one
sed hic unus hic passim
exception you should also be able to
Item poterit exceptio tibi
trust your batteries here Eco alkalines
Hic habeat fiduciam tua eu gravida Eco alkalines
of the world's first and only certified
mundi primus et solus certified
carbon neutral battery manufactured to
neutrum ipsum fabricari, et ad altilium
the highest standards of recycling and
et signa summa redivivus
quality without any trace amounts of
qualis sine ulla copia
harmful chemicals like mercury lead or
noxia chemicals fluctuat argenti uiui aut plumbum
cadmium eco alkalines provide
Eco aurantiacis alkalines providere
performance the rivals leading national
competitores ducit ad perficientur nationalibus
alkaline battery brands at a comparable
stringens in simili brands altilium
price find out more about the Eco
ex pretio invenire magis de Eco
alkalines difference Eco alkalines calm
alkalines difference Eco alkalines cessabit
this is category 5 technology TV want to
V Hoc genus technology vis TV
say greets to everybody who's joining us
salutat qui dicunt suus 'omnes in veniendo
in the chat room tonight I see Brazil JP
chat hac nocte in cubiculum Brazil JP video
jot our Keolis uh you out what hey Jim
nos libet vobis Keolis uh Jim heu quae
Hagg emoto nice to see ya hey Jameson's
Vae adjungentibus domum domui Emoto nice videre Puer heus Jameson est scriptor
are a yes nice to see ya and Dennis
Etiam nice quod sunt videre lente Dennis
Kelly as well awesome hey if color goes
Nullam ut ligula nisi color est amet
on romper room you know she'd look into
romper in cubiculum nosti inspicere illa youd '
that magic tennis racket I see Andrew
tennis reticulo, quod video magicae Andrew
Jamison I see a gamoto and Dennis Kelly
Song: Video Jamieson gamoto et Dennis
yes I also see let me swing cuz this is
ita ego quoque haec viderem me volare coeperit cuz
modern romper room right you gotta swipe
te Redditus est locus iure modern romper ungunt
so we can swipe swipe oh I also see you
sic etiam possumus et utinam te swipe ungunt
al cool dude nice to see you Oh pirate
al nice frigus Dudus te o pirata
rock and damn may do and good to see
et lapis dampnas bonus et non potest videre
y'all okay why this party's getting
Accumsan questus inmunibus huius partis
rough oh I know but while I've got my
Scio autem dum venias aspera Ego got
mobile device in my hand get yours out
ut mobile fabrica est in manu tua sunt
scan this mystical code there it is ibis
scan mysticum hoc codice non est ibi
82 m dot cat5 TV which has got live
LXXXII CAT5 TV m dat vivere quae habet,
video streaming allah youtube if you
YouTube video nisi Allah
want to watch category 5 technology TV
volo ut vigilo TV genus technology V
live on your mobile device but if you're
sed si te vivere in vestri mobile fabrica
driving can't possibly do that oh you
O Vos autem incessus nullo modo possunt,
can possibly but it's not recommended
potest tamen suus commendatur
it's illegal it's dangerous yeah not
Non memini periculosum est nefas
rented by we could ruse a viewer if we
ex conducto inspectoris si possemus ruse
recommend
suadeo
don't want that to happen folks so use
fit uti fieri nolo ut
the listen live feature which is also a
audite et vivet pluma est etiam quod
feature of the mobile app m cabinet
m mobile app pluma de arca
they're just listening they won't get to
ipsi erant 'non iustus audire ad eos
make fun of the bright color of my shirt
facere fun de me clara color de shirt
and the shininess of its Lori and
et shininess sui et Lori
describe the right color of his shirt
describat rectam tunicam color
and whatever those of you who are
quaeque illi qui
listening on radio category 5e on TV
audire ad genus radio 5e in TV
will say his shirt is so vibrant it is
ego autem dico in shirt sit vivat tamque venusta
like the son I am weary glad I'm wearing
sicut filius Taedet me libenter gero
safety green and here let me stand up oh
Quis consurget mihi hic viridis salutem
oh we have look at the Astor Spock yes
o respice ad Carl Spock sic habemus,
how's that we've converted me a
ut, quod weve 'suus' convertimini ad me,
converted him he is indeed an erdling I
et illi quidem ut convertatur in erdling
am a new nerdling okay yeah I'm so proud
ego bene novi nerdling yeah me et superbia
of you man well and this is why we allow
Unde bene damus vobis et
the bright green on the show yeah those
yeah ostendit viridi clara die illa
of you who are listening he's wearing a
suus 'ex vobis qui audiat hoc est circumdatio
Spock shirt and it is 60 green really
Et viridi shirt est vere LX Spock
bright I'm squinting looking over you
Ego respiciens clara LIMUS super vos
yeah you figured this you know and I
tu scis et hoc instar yeah
even figured out the thumb is not in it
et super pollices instar sicco non est in ea
the phone yeah he's been like no man
in phone yeah hes 'been ut nemo hominum
like this no no ask Leonard Nimoy the
Non sic non quaeritur ad Leonard Nimoy
guy who invented it practically and he's
guy qui id confingat utile est scriptor
the guy who's it okay this is what we're
a guy qui suus 'okay sic est quod tu
gonna do is Balkans so yeah live long
'agnus dei esse non Balkan longo vivas tempore et yeah
and prosper folks peace hey did you know
et bene sit pax folks heus tu nosti
the category 5 TV remember the tech
memento quod genus V TV tech
podcast network if it's tech it's here
Si suus 'suus' hic network tech podcasts
and the International Association of
et ex International Association
Internet broadcasters Dave may do it is
Internet broadcasters est, Dave, ut faciam illud
very yellow this shirt I thought it was
Deminutum putavi ipsum flavum
safety green is it safe to yellow it's
flavo viridi tutum est salus
like okay it is so bright it's like mean
ut bene sit clara est et sicut medium
it's like the the highlighter on the end
illud sicut in finem in highlighter
of a highlighter like before you write
highlighter de scribis sicut prius
on the paper desaturate sit a little bit
desaturate sedent super chartam exigua,
but when you like look at this good
at cum te bonum
iridescent to it absolutely yeah it's
Ad venetum deinceps omnino non est yeah
grad to dim the lights folks the studio
ut paulatim caligaverunt lumina studio folks
lights are actually off all the lighting
omnia luminaria off in luminatione sunt in actu,
that you see is from this shirt actually
quem vides ipsum ab hoc shirt
we should have like a radioactive one
ardens tamquam oporteret alterum
actually maybe it is radioactive it's
maybe suus 'vere ardens missus est,
actually a white shirt it's just been
suus 'iustus a album shirt est actually
Dennis yeah yes ok enough of my wardrobe
Ok quod sic Dennis yeah satis vestes meae
malfunctions here
hic seu technicorum
big news for category 5 viewers fans of
V fans of genus in magna fama viewers
Abigail Smith I don't know if we're
Abigail autem Smith nescio si sumus
keeping the Smith or what's happening
aut quid suus 'fieri observatio est Smith
but Abigail got married on Saturday
Abigail autem got duxit sabbatorum
we're very very happy if you saying
nimium felix, si dicis ipsum et nos
she's off the murders oh he's off the
Quæ cum suus 'off O caedes off suus
market sorry guys it sorry fellas all
paenitet enim me paenitet guys foro omnes fellas
right guys yeah I was I had the honor
ego memini me honori ius guys
and pleasure of being there we had the
ibi habuimus et voluptatem
photo booth set up and it was it was
positum fuit tentorium erat photo
really really cool we built this photo
vere frigus hoc photo re we built
booth back on episode number 28 okay he
XXVIII bene res numero esset umbraculum super
says really cool but I can see some of
Dicit vere frigus, sed potest non videre aliquid ex
the pictures yes yes it worked though it
etsi eam, quod sic laboraverunt et quod sic picturas
was fantastic and it was a hit yes
Erat fantastic hit et factum est ita
actually I'll tell you so there's
Et sic illic 'vere dico vobis:
there's the Ferguson clan you know lots
illic 'lots scitis a quo familia Tacitus
and lots of fun the bridal party all
lots of fun, et in omnem partem Sponsaeque
kind of crammed into the the photo booth
photo umbraculum quoddam inculcetur
and then like a clown car more people
ac deinde tamquam ferro rusticus ultra currus populus
decided to join and I don't know how
adiungere voluit, et nesciunt
they fit that many people into a little
multi parum apta ad
five by ten booth but there you have it
quinque decem habeas ibi umbraculum
it actually worked and of course the
Scilicet ex illo actu et laboraverunt
wedding party and Abigail Smith but one
et Abigail uxor Nabal nuptias Smith nisi unus
of the things that was really really
re vera erat, quae de re
neat to realize with the photo booth is
cum photo umbraculum tersus ut animadverto est
that it was so dead simple to use that
quod est ita simplex ut et mortuorum
even a baby can do it oh my before jury
infantem potest etiam de conspectu meo, hoc faciam, o iudices
during well got it about here got the
bene obtinuit quod hic surrexit est per circuitum
picture with that USB button from USB
cum USB eumdem USB a button
button calm that is nice pretty cool
quod est pulchellus frigus nice quod cessabit button
that is nice yes you photo booth was
quod est nice photo, quod sic non esset umbraculum
such a hit that I've already started
Ego iam coepi, quod haec hit
receiving requests for people to rent it
accepto petitiones ad populum tradidit eam custodibus
that we're at the event the world a
qui sumus in hoc mundo sit res
wedding reception which is pretty cool
nuptialem receptionem, quae est pulchellus frigus
we never really thought about that we
Non enim re vera putavit nos ut
joked about it on the show that you know
poterint de hoc scis esse in spectaculum
now that we've invested in the hardware
ut weve 'iam pecuniam in hardware
and the ability to do it yeah I just
facultatem et faciam tibi sicut yeah
rented it well it's kind of cool church
et locavit eam frigus quoque illud genus ecclesia
a thousand bucks number next ten years
arietes mille annos Passage
ago yeah maybe a little longer golden
yeah maybe paulo ante iam auream
but every table had those little cameras
Vestibulum sed parum mensas
were you yes female the camera back and
Etiam diam et feminam eras
they'd thank you your pictures yeah or
vellem autem tuus imagines yeah, aut gratias ago tibi,
or is what we i I don't I think it was
ego autem non sum, non puto quod factum est
my wedding I'm pretty sure was that we
Im 'pulchellus certus sum autem quod nuptias meas
did you remember your anniversary date
meministi tuam et date anniversary
I'm just trying to get them in trouble
Im 'iustus trying impetro in tribulatio
here no I I do and do it but I'm trying
hic non ego facio, et faciam: sed Im 'trying
I'm pretty sure it was our wedding but
Im 'pulchellus certus non erat nostrum nuptialem
it may have been a like another family
ut non fuerit similis alterius familiae
members wedding but I do recall the
ego autem membra nuptialem quae praedixi
disposable
PROMPTU
yes on the table i think it was us it
Sed puto quod nobis in mensa
was cool I you got a lot yes picture
Et quod sic frigus erat, et got multus picture
totally us yeah so then everybody took
Tulit igitur omnibus, ut prorsus nos yeah
pictures around the table so you got all
sic obtinuit omnem circa mensam in imaginibus
these candid shots no it was my
nihil mihi fuit haec candida impetum ictibus exactis occidentes
brother's wedding because they were in
quia in nuptiis fratris
kilts and I remember some particular
et recordabor kilts aliquo particular
photos although that will not ever leave
quod etsi non semper abire photos
the family way to go bro so
ut familia iter bro
congratulations to Abigail Smith and her
gratulatione ad Abigail uxor eius et Smith
new husband Kyle page as well so if you
et novus maritus Kyle quoque pagina, si
would like Abigail has given you the
vellem autem Abigail dedit tibi
viewers of category 5 technology TV and
V genus technology quod TV visores
exclusive behind-the-scenes view of the
post-the-scaenarum de sententia exclusive
ceremony itself go on to her bile a
ceremonia se vado ut a sua bilis inest,
category 5 TV you can actually watch the
V ad vigilate TV audistis, cernere oculis genus
wedding ceremony if you care to and make
et si quaeris nuptias
sure you send your greetings if you'd
salutem tuam debeas si curaris
like to send in a card or whatever our
ut quicquid vel mittere tabella
address our mailing address is at the
Duis tempus ipsum sit in nostra address
bottom of the website category 5e vegan
imo quod 5e vegan genus website
just send a greeting card or congratula
nunc mitte et congratula cards
tory note or whatever you like to do or
nota facere velis sive candidissimo
simply an email at abbey at category or
in an email ad solum genus aut abbatia
Abigail pardon me at category 5 10 you
V ad X genus veniam autem Abigail Carmelitide
do what I typically do is I forget about
Ego enim sum nolite oblivisci circa quod typically
it for so long it just seems
tamdiu enim apparet
inappropriate to sender yeah a message
Mittens yeah alienum est nuntius
and I'm horrible I'm a horrible person
et ego non sum necessarie hominem dirum quod foedam
uh oh yeah your granite day was three
O dies autem tres uh yeah tuum granite
weeks ago happy birthday hey you know
ante diem natalem felicem hebdomades heus tu nosti
what I user episode 297 right yes it is
quae res usor etiam est jus CCXCVII
I was here for 295 to yes cuz he's
CCXCV ad me huc ad hoc quod sic est cuz
having trouble with co-hosts these days
habens tribulationis cum Stephani co-moderatores hos dies
am i well you know I know they are
ego ego scio bene te novi sunt,
difficult it you know are dealing with
ut cognoscatis, quae circa difficile
let's see Hilary got married last year
videamus tandem got duxit Hillarii anno,
was that true yeah no Abby have a Gil
yeah verum est, quod non habent coenobium Gil
yeah I think somebody'll Krista just got
Yeah puto somebody'll fautorum iustus got
away into slams on the last episode of
auferet, in ultima episodes de slams
carry five yeah here we go okay all
hic nos omnes bene memini ferre quinque
right we want to welcome our new viewers
nova enim dextra volunt nostri receperint viewers
tonight who have registered on our
qui descripserunt hac nocte nobis
website category five dot TV who have we
qui dat nobis quinque TV genus website
got we have naked cook and I can tell
et nudi sumus Dico autem cocus
you from experience that is a dangerous
ab experientia, quod periculo est,
thing to do when you're frying bacon
est ut faciam tibi sartaginem cum lardum
definitely is it make a cook or naked
planto certus est nudum coquo
kook I think it's a book I think that
Ego illud puto esse librum Georgii politicum
would do kook with a cake all right but
sed et fragmen massae recte facturos Kook
well just one anyway all slicked oz
tum sicut quis usquam oz omnis slicked
tough well there's a couple of eyes in
ibi quoque duos oculos durus
the middle and geeks or seeks will say
argutatores non quaerit media et dicent tibi
yes on clothes Marie awesome all right
maria omnia mirabilia Etiam vestimenta
zip I'm going with as if as if is easy
Ego quasi avi, quasi facilis
thanks Holly going zip nice to see ya
nice quod gratias ago Holly ad zip ya videre
sparks all right and I'll go cypher
Et omnis congregatio flammis dextram et ibo notis
excellent or is a happy fun i'll go
Ego ibo ut beatus sit amet, est optimum nec
super good planning on the you know the
Super bono consilio a te cognoscere
third last syllable rule you know that's
tertia syllaba ultima regula est et scitis
why you get you know folks like radio
cur tu adepto folks quasi radio scitis
netherlands at two in the morning you
Netherlands et ad duos in mane
know you hear words like controversy
auditis sermonibus controversia sicut scitis
because the rules suggest isn't that
quia non est qui praecepta suadeant
right job okay well i don't want to
tam bene officium rectum quod non vis
start any controversy here so let's move
quid hic sic lets 'satus controversia moventur
on indeed all right well tonight we are
immo etiam hac nocte super omnem enim recti sunt,
going to show you how to use the gimp to
Ad quam uti et tibi est scribus
crow is our feature feature yeah right
cantet ter noster pluma pluma ius yeah
we talked all about the gimp we're going
scribus loquebatur ad omnem circa nos erant 'iens
to show you some tricks and we're gonna
ut ostenderet tibi aliquid fraudesque dolusque sumus agnus dei
show you a way to add depth of field
tibi ita addere profundum agro
your photo in what 15 minutes no in like
XV minuta tamquam in quo nulla est in photo
15 seconds ah so have to pay attention
XV ah tam seconds ad attendere
the GIMP is a free piece of software you
piece of software tibi liberum est in GIMP
can get it at gimp.org i'm gonna bring
Im 'agnus dei adepto adducere possit ad gimp.org
up their website just to show you around
in eorum website tantum ostendere circumagam te
just really really quickly here alright
sicut rem vere hic cito alright
gimp.org there you go we've got
Comperto gimp.org te ibi
downloads over on the right-hand side
a dextris super Downloads
find it all about it and this is for
invenient eum omnia de eo et haec est enim
linux this particular version they've
linux poema maxime quod est illis operum
got all different versions of linux that
ut omnem uaria Linux
are accessible you've got a boon to
nunc demum istaec nata sunt accessible impetratur
debian open suse whatever and then if
et sic patet quod suse Debian
you want to run this on windows there is
in hoc volo ut run vestri fenestras sunt
a windows version all you have to do is
et fenestras omne poema facere in vobis est
go to gimp dash win dot sourceforge.net
scribus unquam offendas ad sourceforge.net dat win
don't whatever type the I know origin it
quidquid est generis originem non novi illum
quick they used to have the windows in
solebant habere ad fenestras velox apud
the mac version also available in their
et de Mac version available in sua
downloads page I don't know why they've
Nescio quid habent downloads page
changed that I know its third parties
mutata quod sciam partes eius tertius
that create these installers but there
sed quod creare haec installers
it is for windows gimp dash win dot
scribus infusa est per fenestras dat win
sourceforge.net and you'll be able to
sourceforge.net et youll poterit
get the installer for gimp for windows
ut per installer propter scribus ad fenestras
you can download that version now that
Quod poema iam quod vos can download
is for any version of windows that you
nam si is qui te fenestras versionem
okay so so you can get chinese
ut bene ut vos can adepto Seres
simplified croatian danish that's the
facilius est qui Danish Crovatica
help files but can we get the help for
et files potest auxilium ad auxilium dabimus tibi
in comes with English know is that 11 no
XI, quod fit cum in Anglis nemo scit hoc
that's not what are you talking about it
huius tu neque auctoritatem, quod non de illo
you can just give me a hard time I'm
da mihi Difficile potes me
just giving your heart so i'll give you
sic ego praecipio tibi dabo vobis cor tuum, sicut
a hard time back yeah okay yeah all
Difficile ad omnem memini memini purus
about the GIMP and okay I'm not going to
Im 'non iens ut bene et de GIMP
comment about what you're acting like
comment about quid tu facis
I'm happening hey check out my cup is
Heus Im fieri reprehendo hoc poculum meum
even start I know you are like the bomb
satus es tu scis et sicut tibi in bomb
tonight like geek guy awesome there's a
noctem quasi cursum illic 'a guy horribilis
language missing there I'm helpful
Im 'non defuit linguae utile
you're gonna make me say during Klingon
amet in me tu dicis Klingonica
yes it's gotta be you gotta translate it
te Redditus est nobis interpretari potest, quod sic suus 'Redditus est
if you want to donate your time okay
Si bene vis ut datum tempus tuam
well I mean that we were talking to you
ut bene sit nobis cum, quod loquitur ad vos
yeah yeah the translator last time yeah
yeah yeah interpres in novissimis diebus yeah
well that was one usually been 95 all
quia omnes unum XCV consuerant
right bingo fix it you can but he
sed non potestis iustum bingo fix
digresses yeah mwah yeah all right I'm
yeah digreditur Mwah yeah omnes recti me
gonna bring out GNU image manipulation
agnus dei imago GNU adducere de manipulation
program on my computer i run linux so
in computatrum progressio mea ego curram ut Linux
I've just simply installed it using the
Ego simpliciter iustum est installed usura a
synaptic package manager you can install
Receptor vos can install sarcina sit amet
it with apt-get or whatever package
aut quod aptum natum est esse sarcina, accipere
manager program that you're using so
procurator progressio ut erant 'usura est
here we go GNU image manipulation
Nunc ad imaginem GNU manipulation
program 2.8 is the version that I'm
progressio 2,8 version, quod est a me
currently running and there we go I'm
et currens non sum currently imus,
running in multi window mode which I
modus currit et in qua multi fenestra
prefer especially because most of the
plerique malunt maxime
time when I'm working in a Productivity
Im 'opus in tempore, cum Uber
environment I have multiple monitors so
multa habeo igitur monitores amet
I love to have my work on one screen and
Amo ad ex una screen et opus meum
my tools on another screen because it
quia alia in screen instrumenta mea
just freeze up the space and it gives me
in frigore et iustum spatium mihi
a clear working space basically so I
ut patet per basically spatium working
like that there is a single like a
quod simile est sicut unum
single windowed mode as well that's a
tum quod sit unum modus windowed
little bit more comfortable for I
modicum aliquantulus magis comfortable pro me
suppose that I've seen your
putant quia vidi te
windows-based sometimes asteroids on the
fenestras, fundatur in interdum asteroides
other woman yeah yeah but that may be
sed quod sit mulieri aliter yeah yeah
more comfortable for you if you want to
magis comfortable, si tibi vis
put it in single window mode if you're
posuit eum in fenestra uno mode, si vestri '
like a Photoshop user just to get you
sicut Photoshop user ut iustus te
kind of into using the game that can be
quae potest esse genus in ludum usura
done by simply clicking on Windows and
quod fieri solum clicking in Fenestra
then single window mode that will switch
quod modus erit una fenestra switch
things around so I've got some pictures
quae et Ego got circa aliquas imaginibus
Eric you mentioned that you were on the
Eric pro qua locutus es, qui erant in te,
show back on 295 right so let's grab a
retro monstrare CCXCV justum capto scriptor
picture from that
imago ab illo
we'll open it up in the gng so is
tibi nos aperire, sic est in gng
wearing a little different colored green
veste viridi paulo diversicolores
that yeah there you go these photos of
memini enim hae imagines Grat
course are available in the in the show
utique non available in autem in spectaculum
notes for episode number 2 95 through
in Episode II notas numerus per XCV
our new gallery system and what we want
Art Gallery nostra ratio, et volumus quod
to do is we want to you know typical
est enim vis ut faciam tibi scit typical
camera what it does is it makes
Quid est enim quod facit camera
everything generally in focus so if
quae si ita plerumque in focus
you're looking at a grand vista with a
ad magnificum et quaeritis Vista
couple of people in the foreground
duobus hominibus fabrica
doesn't matter it's all going to be in
Tota refert in futurum
focus and so you don't get that kind of
et sic qui quaedam non ut focus
sense of depth of field so we're going
profundum agro sensus sic erant 'iens
to actually create that in our studio
ut ipse bene creo quia in bulla
here what happens is that you know the
hinc est, quod te scire quid accidit
back wall is so close to us that it
ita propinqua ut paries ad
doesn't create a depth of field so we
profundum agro ad creare non est ita et nos
don't get that so the first thing I want
qui primus rem ita volo et non habetis:
to do in the camp is do something that's
Est aliquid quod non est in castris
kind of unique we're going to create a
genus a unique erant 'iens creo
very very simple vignette and the
ipsum simplex et vignette
vignette is just a way to bring our
vignette est a modo ad nostram adducere
characters are our focal subjects of the
arx nostrorum ingenia sunt subiecti
photograph forward so that it looks like
ut videtur procedere flavi
they are really the focus of the
sunt ad focus in vere
photograph it really draws your eye to
ad COMMEDITOR eam rem trahit oculi tui
the person or the the subject Viet a
in persona sive in re Vict
bird or a flower whatever it is a
quod in flore vel avem est
vignette will really help to draw the
et vere adiuvet ad hauriendam vignette
eye to one particular thing so in this
unius rei in oculo
case we have two subjects it's Eric and
causa est quia habemus duas, et Eric
I so I'm going to use a round you know
Ego scio, sic Im 'iens ut uti a te undique
elliptical marquee here and simply
Marquee ellipticis tantum huc
create a circle that's roughly a little
creare circulus quod paulo durius
bit bigger than my head that's a big one
quod suus 'a magnus partem maior quam unum caput meum
oh yeah well then the same thing for
Ergo idem est O Yeah
Eric that's a bigger one and I can go
Eric quod est unum et non possum ire maior
like that i can actually with the gimp
sicut quod non possum esse cum scribus
see i can create to marquis by doing
videre possum facere, creare et marchionem
what I'm first when I click I just drag
Quid ego primus et ego click, cum ego iustus drag
and drop let go and I can move that
et stillabunt moventur ut possint et dimiserit
around and I can here's one of the nice
suus 'nice quod hic non possum et in circuitu unum
things about the gimp i can actually
omnia possum etiam de scribus
resize my marquee can't do that with
Marquee Sedeo meis non faciam cum eo
photoshop and then to create a second
et tunc creare a secunda forum
one I can holding my left shift key and
I sinistram non est meum tenebant, et Shift key
then click and drag and create the
et tunc click extraho quod creare
second one and now I can in fact move
et tamen secundus motus possum
just the second one without affecting
non solum secundum bonum pertinent,
over and the first one so now I can make
et primo modo possum
that so that it works a little bit
ut faciat quod paulo
better with Erics noggin okay so now I
melius est ut bene nunc Erics noggin
want to do something that is going to
quid vis ut faciam tibi quae ventura sunt
make it so that things are not stark
ut non ea quae summae
because now if I were to fill in a
quod si possem imple
vignette it would have a very definitive
ipsum definitum esset a vignette
line where that mark
Ubi nota linea
ends so we're going to create what is
fines etiam sic erant 'iens creo quod
called a feather on that selection so
Itaque pinna dicitur in electione
I'm going to go right click and go
Ego vadam ad dextram et ibo click
select feather and we're going to
Pluma et eligere erant 'iens
observe the dimensions of our image this
magnitudinem obseruare hanc imaginem
image is you know 20 200 pixels wide by
Imago elementa scitis XX CC ab wide
1300 pixels high so this particular our
MCCC summus elementa maxime est huius nostri,
first feather we're going to make this
Pluma prius erant 'iens ut hoc
rather huge and again this is something
et adhuc magis quod sit aliquid ingens
you can't do with Photoshop we're going
non potes facere cum Photoshop erant 'iens
to make it 1,000 pixels which sounds
1000 ut elementa sonare
crazy but this gives us something really
sed dat nobis aliquid realiter rabidus
really neat watch what happens here so
Vigilate itaque quid hic vere tersus
now I'm going to now that I've done that
Eo modo, ut hactenus factum, quod Ego
we're going to right-click and I'm going
click erant 'iens ut dextra ego vado
to go select invert and then create a
ut lego contrarium mutât et tunc creare
new layer transparent and fill that with
ut perspicuum iacuit nova replere
black and you'll see that what I've
quod youll 'animadverto ut nigrum, et quia commune aut inmundum
effectively done is simply darkened out
factum est simpliciter et efficaciter tenebrescens obscurabitur
the entire photo but you can see even on
sed etiam potest totum Photo
your screen there that my face and
screen, quod vestri est, et vultus meus
Eric's face are just ever so slightly
Et facies sicut Eric utcunque parum
brighter more more prominent in the
multo plus lucidiores sunt super principem esse
photograph so everything else is
ergo omne aliud esse imaginem photographicam
darkened right up can't really see the
tenebris obscuratum dextra usque videre potest realiter
photo but we can see that our faces are
quae nobis non possumus videre facies sint, sed photo
there so now that we've created that
et quod creatum est iam ut weve '
really massive 1000 pixel vignette so
vere ingens M pixel et vignette
this is a almost a gradient of blackness
haec est enim fere nigri coloris gradiente
into lightness so so much so that it is
adeo leve quod in tantum
absolutely fluid there's no edges to it
illic 'nullum omnino liquidum margine eius
or anything like that so now that we've
aut quicquam simile est enim iam ut weve '
done that we're going to again circle my
cingi meum factum est iens
head circle Eric's head and it can be
Eric circulo caput capitis quod illud potest esse
rough it doesn't have to be close at all
omnino finem non esse aspera
like just you know roughly our heads and
sicut scitis justum, et delicta nostra creverunt usque roughly
I'm going to right-click and now i'm
Im 'iens ut ius click, et nunc sum
going to change the feather i'm going to
Im 'iens mutare ad quod Pluma
create a new feather and we're going to
Pluma partum a novus et erant 'iens
make this one quite a bit smaller we're
hoc unum satis aliquantulus minor sumus
going to make this 250 pixels and i'm
Im 'iens hoc quod elementa CCL
just going to cut and you'll see what
nunc videbis quae facturus sectis
that is done is it's really brought out
suus 'vere factum esse eduxerunt
our heads so now that we've got that
et delicta nostra creverunt usque nunc Comperto quod
form of a vignette we can play around
forma vignette possumus ludere circum
with the opacity of this layer advice
accumsan id consilium cum opacitate
you know you notice that i actually have
scio ego animadverto ut vos habere in actu
that layer selected and to show you what
ut ostenderet quid uellent accumsan
that layer in fact looks like it's
eo quod abdito vultus amo suus '
literally that so i'm going to drag the
ibo ut litteram grauibus
opacity of that layer so that we can
quod iacuit, ut possumus; Opacitas
change how much the background is
mutata quantum background est
affected by that there we are
affectus qui sunt ibi
and we can change even the mode to just
et mutare non possumus quidem modus est iustus
simply dark him there we are and we can
ibi eum solum obscura sunt non potest
just continue to bring that down bring
Iustus permanere in esse producat adducere
it up however we want but you notice our
sed usque tamen non volunt illud animadverto nostrum
faces never change its only the
mutata facies eius non modo
surrounding areas to create that really
quod realiter creare circuitum areas
nice vignette to draw your eye more
grata magis oculum ad hauriendum vignette
toward the the subjects of the photo so
ut ad subditorum Photo
now to create that kind of
Nunc autem creare genus
three-dimensional effect that we're
tres dimensiva effectus non sumus
going for i'm going to temporarily
Im 'iens ut iret usque ad tempus
disable that layer and i can just make
quia iustus disable strato possum facere
my canvas just a little bit bigger here
hie mihi maior pariete tantum exigua,
so that i can get it onto the outside
ita ut ego potest adepto onto de foris
edges and i'm going to use the this
Im 'iens ut uti hoc a marginibus &amp;
marquee up here that's a lasso and that
Ascende huc, quae LAQUEUM et a PRAETORIUM
allows me to drag my mouse and so with
mus et sic patitur me traho
the gimp what i can do is i can click in
scribus quid possum facere possum quod per click
a single spot and then it gives me this
hoc uno loco me tum
line and once I've clicked there now I
statim ac linea Ego coniuctionem pressisti est nunc
can click click click and I can go like
click non possunt ire sicut et ego click click
that or I can hold in and I can actually
quia non possum tenere non possum: et in actually
just trace around notice that i do not
mox circum fastigia rerum notitiam quae ego facio
have to be anywhere close yeah you want
uelit esse vis Yeah
to be kind of you know close to the ship
nosti genus proximum navi fieri
clip middle is there buddy well sorry
dolet etiam non buddy medium video
we'll fix it okay so I don't need to be
si te bene figere, ita ut non opus sit
precise in any way because remember
memento quod ullo modo precise
we're doing what I'm showing you tonight
Ego ostendam tibi quae erant 'facere hac nocte
is the world's easiest fastest way to do
mundi velocissimo est facillimus via ut faciam
this and I'm also going to grab the the
Im 'iens ut etiam in hac et in capto
edge of the eco alkaline sign there to
ibi partem signi eco stringens
complete our effect so now I've got that
nunc demum istaec nata est perficere effectum nostrae
Marky and if I right click and select
Marky et si recta et click eligere
and now feather and again we want this
plumas detrahere et nunc iterum atque vis nobis est
feather to be a little bit smaller than
pluma est paulo minus
the last one we're going to make this
ultima quis erant 'iens ut hoc
100 pixels keeping in mind that this is
C elementa dum in eo est
all relative to the fact that our photo
ad omne id quod photo
is 2200 pixels by 1300 pixels so if
Sic elementa in MCCC non elementa MMCC
you've got a photo that is 640 by 480
tu got a photo ut a CDLXXX DCXL
obviously a thousand pixel feather is
Pluma est mille manifesto pixel
going to be ridiculous because that is
Ridiculum est quod futurum
actually better than your photograph so
etiam sic melior est te scan
relatively speaking the first feather
secundum quid primi Pluma
that we did was approximately a half of
non fecit, quod erat circiter dimidium
the pixel width of the the document the
et latitudinem loci ad documentum de pixel
image the second one that we did was
secundum imaginem eius, qui fecit nos,
roughly a quarter no an eighth of that
Nemo fere octava parte illius
and now we're doing it just you know a
et nunc sicut scitis quod in hoc discis
very very subtle kind of feathering here
hic nimis subtili quodam fummo
so with that feather of 100 pixels which
Pluma de C, quod cum elementa quibus
I've done okay so now i'm going to right
Ego autem fit bene et recte Im 'iens
click and go select invert and i'm going
click quod lego ire contrarium mutât et ego vado
to copy and paste ctrl c ctrl v and then
ut effingo quod crustulum c accidit et accidit v
i'm going to right click and go layer 2
Im 'iens ut orci right click and II
new layer just so that i can show you
novus layer ita non possum tibi
what i've actually
Ego enim actually
done now I've actually copied the wrong
Ego autem fieri iniuriam ultro illorum adlata evidentem
thing see what's happened there so with
quid inde factum est ita
GIMP I can control Z control Z control Z
GIMP possum control Z imperium z Z imperium
but here in canada we say it'd sure make
in Canada sed hic certus ut dicere vellem facere
sure that I copy the right thing invert
certus ut effingo quod rectum est contrarium mutât
that again copy paste layer to new layer
iterum effingo quod crustulum ut novum stratum algarum
turn that off and you see that the
qui conversus et videtis quod off
people are gone the man around stays
sedet populi sunt circum hominem
okay the operation so that now has
bene habet ad operationem ut iam
created this extra layer here all right
hoc creavit omnia recta hic susicivus layer
and now what I want to do is I want to
et nunc quid tibi vis facere cupio
actually blur that layer but before I do
etiam ardua, quae tamen ante lavacrum facio
that here's the trick I want to make
quod hic 'furta facere cupio
sure that it doesn't blur over top of
certus quod non est in summo ex LABES
our faces over top and I remember that I
et meminisse me vertice super faciem nostram
made that mark ii and then I feathered
II, quod fecit signum et ego qucs
that Marky so it has a nice soft edge so
qui sic habet a nice mollis in ore gladii tam Marky
what I actually want to do is I want to
ego actu non quid vis ut faciam tibi cupio
tell it that I don't want it to go
ad ea quae nolo ut vadam
outside of the transparency so I want to
Perspicuum autem est extra cupio
lock the alpha channel on this
Alpha claudunt hanc channel
particular layer lock alpha channel okay
lamina maxime bene clausum Alpha channel
so I've just clicked that button up
Ego iustus clicked usque adeo ut button
there so now if I right click and
si modo rectum est click
whatever I do to this layer let's say I
quod ego facio huic algarum lets 'narro
fill the whole thing in with black watch
nigrum in vigilia impleret omnia
what happens it just fills that layer so
quod fit hoc modo implet, ita quod iacuit
it gives you a perspective as to what is
dat quoad prospectus
actually happening there so now I'm
actu est non ut nunc sum,
going to right-click and I'm going to go
Im 'iens recta-click atque iturus
filters blur Gaussian blur and this
Filtra et ardua Gaussian LABES
gives us a nice little close-up preview
nobis praevisum iucunumque propinquus-sursum
and you can drag around and just change
et in circuitu, et ipsi trahunt vos can iustus commutationem
that to a reasonable amount of blur to
rationabile, quae ad moles ad LABES
give you that depth of field that you're
Agrum do tibi es altitudine
looking for what's driven so it goes and
et quid quaero quidem pulsus
burn some of the others that you might
Alii autem ut adoleret
use well each one is is using different
utor tam unumquodque quod est per aliud
kind of filtering techniques right so a
ita ius ars quaedam percolatur
Gaussian blur you imagine that is like a
Gaussian LABES hoc est imaginari sicut tu
like a beer goggle kind of everything is
sicut omne genus dolor goggle
diffused okay but it's it's even across
sed suus 'etiam per illud bene diffunditur
the whole image something like a motion
Omnis motus tamquam
blur for example you as the name would
ardua enim exemplum quod tibi nomen esset,
entail is something that would have a
hoc est quod habere aliquid adferunt:
bit of a stretch to it where a Gaussian
a quo factum est in libris de rebus Gaussian
blur is literally just a blur on the
LABES ad litteram iustus a LABES
image almost as if your camera were out
si extra cameram imaginem propemodum
of focus so that's what i'm doing here
ita ut 'quis ego sum facis, hic focus est
is i'm actually creating that out of
Im 'creando esse in actu, ut ex
focus effect on that background because
eo quod background effectus focus
that's exactly what you would do with
prorsus ut 'quid esset facturus est
changing your f-stop on a high-end
mutantur, f vestris nolite super summus finem
cameras blur the background to give you
cameras background LABES ad vos
that depth of field look we're having to
habens profunditatem erant agrorum spectant
do it digitally after the fact
digitally faciam cum eo
okay so by having change the horizontal
ut bene per horizontalem habens mutare
and vertical blur radius I've set mine
et radii vertical LABES Ego posuit mea
to 10 you can see the difference there
X ut possis videre quid sit non
that's what it looks like normally and
quis is vultus amo ut suus 'Northmanni, et
when I let go that's the preview so now
et nunc est, quod dimittet cum preview
if I hit OK you'll actually see that
si ledo OK te quoque videre
things have in fact changed and there is
et omnia quae in eo mutata sit
a bit of a soft blur on the brick so now
aliquantulus of a LABES in latere et nunc mollis
reorder my layers make sure that the
reorder me fac quod laminis
dark vignette is on the very very top of
ipsa est summum tenebrae vignette
the image and now I turn on that layer
et conversus est imago nunc accumsan
and I end up with that now that's a bit
et iam non terminus sursum quod suus 'aliquantulus
too dark for my photo so I'm going to
etiam Im 'iens ut tenebris tam in photo mei
actually bring down the opacity and
in opaco illo et sunt actualiter inducant
again this just brings out our our faces
vultus nostros iterum iustorum
a little bit and that gives us a real
exigua, et dederit nobis ipsa
kind of perspective that where the
perspective ubi id genus
subjects of the photo the background is
subjectis in background est photo
is slightly blurred and the vignette
et paulo oculorum vignette
creates this effect that gives us that
facit quod facit effectum
kind of pops us right out of the photo
photo de iustitia quoddam operculum
very nice literally as simple as that so
nice quod simplex, ut sic stricte recipienda est
how quickly can we make this effect well
quomodo possumus facere cito hunc modum etiam
let's start over we're going to bring up
lets 'satus per erant' iens sursum adducere
that photo so I'm going to just
quod photo iustus ita Im 'iens
demonstrate for you how quickly this can
demonstrabo tibi quam hoc non potest cito
be done let's go back your own show to
ad tuam ostende fieri abeamus
money from 0 to 95 photos okay so with
XCV imaginibus sic est purus pecunia 0
that photo open here's what we're gonna
photo quod est quod hie open 'agnus dei sumus
do we're gonna highlight my head
agnus dei non erant efferre caput meum
highlight Eric's head start again there
CAPUT Eric rursus caput est
we go I like my head there we go okay
imus ego ut vadam bene caput meum ibi
feather
pluma
we're doing like half of the proper yeah
erant 'facere media tanquam de propriis yeah
thousand I'm going on down two thousand
Ego deinceps duo milia
yeah half of the pixels of my the width
yeah dimidium meae sunt elementa in latitudine
of my image or so doesn't really make a
imaginis vitae meae aut non realiter facere
difference okay and then select invert
bene distinctus tunc lego Portae
remember I've already shown you how to
memento Ego ostensum est prius quam te
do this but I'm just showing you how
Im 'iustus tamen Ego ostendam tibi quid hoc facere
quickly you can in fact create this very
hanc non potest creare nimis celeriter quidem
same effect so we're taking a photo and
eundem effectum, et sic erant 'accipiens photo
actually enhancing it quite a bit making
actually enhancing satis aliquantulus faciendo eam
a look pretty nice feather this time
hoc bellum nice pluma speculati
we're going to 250 pixels or so in my
erant 'iens ut CCL vel ita in elementa
particular image there we go get er down
maxime imago est er ut et imus,
around 40 before than you yeah well
circiter XL prius quam te bene yeah
whatever going to use you you get the
quod vos adepto in vestri 'iens ut
feel just by looking at the photo and
iustus vultus in photo et a sentiunt
get in that sense of how you want it to
ut in eo sensu in quo vis eam
look alright sorry your time and me
ecce tempus tuum, licet paenitet me
we've been about what 30 seconds so far
circiter XXX seconds usque quod habuimus
careful with that nose yeah careful
cave diligenter ne nasus yeah
up and around down click and Collect and
et in circuitu, et click et Oratione
then shift to select my second mark ii
tum migrandum est mihi secundum signum eligere II
left shift key there we go select
Shift key ad sinistram non eligere possumus
feather 100 pixels invert that selection
plumas detrahere, quae lectio C elementa genio invertere
so that i can copy the background paste
ego potest effingo quod crustulum background
it and create a new layer from that
et quod partum a novus layer ut a
pasted layer and I've done it again did
Addiderunt autem feci strato crustulum
the OP convert wrong thing yeah oh
OP yeah conversum est in malum O
that's right I didn't need to invert no
Quod suus 'ius tibi non opus ultra ac genio invertere
that's right which one if I got right
Quod si recte surgens unus
now edit there okay that's what I
Nunc illud est quod creare est okay sum
actually want there we are okay perfect
bene vis perfectus esse non sumus
let's make that alpha channel locked
channel clausa beta, quod faciamus
we're gonna blur it gaussian blur I'm
suus 'agnus dei sumus LABES gaussian LABES me
gonna make it a little bit heavier this
suus 'agnus dei paululum gravius faciam istud
time than our first example is then yeah
Exemplum primi memini tunc temporis
just so that it's a little more apparent
manifestum est quod tam parum
to you at home watching this if you're
Si vestri 'domi vigilo haec tibi
watching it on a smaller screen there we
vigilantes in ea minor screen ibi
go we're going to pop right out of that
ad pop erant 'iens ut rectum de illo
picture so now we've actually created
ut iam diximus esse imaginem creatus est
this effect look at Eric how he just
quam ipse iustus vultus ad hunc modum Eric
kind of pops out of that picture and
operculum e genus pictura
I've been really really sloppy with it
Ego vere vere fuisse SORDIDUS in ea
just for the sake of the demonstration
iusta de causa demonstrationem
you can get in a little bit tighter you
vos can adepto tarn exigua sunt in vobis,
see how you know part of Spock is still
Video quomodo tu scis adhuc partem Spock
in focus but you can get in tighter and
sed ut focus in te potest, artius atque
actually fix that up but for the sake of
quidem statuere, sed propter
the demonstration you can really see how
vos can vere videre quam demonstrationem
that very subtle blur and that vignette
quae inrepit et vignette blur
has kind of popped Eric out of that
qui de genere est papaver Eric
photo let's look again at that with you
Intueamur photo cum in illo
know let's just use air because the
lets 'iustus utor in aura, quia ignorans
example because I think he's the better
exemplum puto, quod non est bonum
example between the two of us on that
exempli gratia inter nos duo illa
particular sample so there he is let's
ibi est maxime specimen, ita lets '
turn off all the effects that's how flat
averte omnes effectus ut 'quam plana
the photo did look see how everything is
quid existis videre vultus in photo est omne
in touch won't i handsome looking for he
ego autem non quaero pulcher in tactus cum
is you know there is turn back on our
qui conversus est retro in nobis non scitis
effect there we go nice and simple and
nice quod simplex et imus, et effectus est
all done using free tools the GNU image
omnia libera utens tools fieri imaginis GNU
manipulation program you can download it
progressio vos can download hoc manipulation
a gimp.org check it out you can download
Vos can reprehendo eam per gimp.org download
it today right there gimp.org for linux
quod hodie est rectum in gimp.org Linux
and again i'm going to put the link in
iterumque Im 'iens ad induendum vinculum in
the show notes maybe we can post it in
ostendunt notas post maybe nos in eam
the chat
ad chat
chat room as well GIMP dash win dot
chat cubiculum de latibulis surrexissent GIMP etiam dat win
sourceforge.net that's where you'll get
id est quo youll 'adepto sourceforge.net
it for microsoft windows there is a mac
et fenestras ejus Microsoft est a Mac
version available as well unfortunately
tum quod valde dolendum version available
i don't have the link to that but i'm
ego autem non sum, quod est vinculum
sure you can find that fairly quickly
certus ut vos can reperio satis cito
they are a resourceful bunch of yeah and
Gaudete et consilii sunt fasciculum
it's open source it's free and it's
liberi et aperta fonte illud suus 'suus'
available to you right now so all right
nunc ergo praesto omnibus iure tibi
why don't we go to news sounds good all
Quin imus bene sonat novitatibus
right well football manager is a
tam jus sit amet eu est
football management simulation game
eu ludum administratione simulation
where players by cell built and train
cellulam, ubi ædificata fuerit, et scaenicos, per agmen
the ultimate football team and play them
et in quadrigis ludere in ultima eu eos
against others in various tournaments
et in variis aliis in torneamentis
and come with a ma tante op the game is
cum tante op ludum et ma
made by Sports Interactive and published
et factum est a ludis editis Interactive
by Sega and is a continuation of the
Sega et per continuationem
championship manager series started in
In sit amet pilae coepi seriem
1989 by the same developers the game
MCMLXXXIX, a developers eodem ludum
developers have announced that the next
developers et nuntiatum est altera
incarnation of the popular simulation
popularibus incarnatione singulariter completur simulation
will support linux nice thanks to steam
gratias ago tibi grata vapor Linux suscipio
the game will be available to buy on one
emere ludum erit available in unum
platform but install and play on all you
platform install sed in omnibus, et ludere
won't need to buy it again to play on
non opus est tibi ut emas a adhuc ludere
your Mac or Windows machines the Linux
vestri Mac vel Linux in Fenestra machinis
release will also support connecting
release etiam support connectens
with and playing against Mac and PC
et cum ludens et in PC Mac
users football manager 2014 is expected
eu amet users MMXIV expectat
to release sometime around October very
nunc circa ipsum Octobris dimittere
cool now I won't pretend that I'm a
refrigescant, quae iam non sum in simulare
sports guy you know you would have
ludis habent esse guy vos scitis
probably even pretending oh sorry but
Paenitet, sed probabiliter utinam et dolo
now i cant pretend that because i can
Nunc quia i Cant simulare non possum
get you know that awesome application so
scio te qui applicationem et horribilis
but what what I think this does with
sed quid est hoc, quod cum puto
football manager is it it shows again
eu enim sit amet est autem rursus ostendit
windows users Mac users that all of a
a Mac users ut Fenestra users
sudden linux is a viable platform for
Est viable quia platform subito Linux
their favorite games because this is a
hic ventus ludis
popular game I mean fantasy football and
popularibus eu ludum, et non sit fantasy
being able to track your teams and play
esse potest ad track tuam et teams ludere
against other people that's a pretty
in aliis quod 'a pulchellus
popular thing and so now to have it on
res vulgaris et iam habere eam
linux and being cross compatible with
Crucis et commodum Linux
mac and windows and then all of a sudden
deinde repente fenestrae Mac
people start to realize hey this is this
heu populus satus ut animadverto quod hoc est,
is viable well because i think gaming is
Puto quod est viable bene sit gaming
a big thing that holds people back from
continet magnum de populis
trying out linux and steam is going to
vapor est ad quaerit ex Linux
make a difference is already making a
iam facta amet
difference
difference
I think people are already starting to
Ego autem iam incipiens ad populum
see that and and here's another one nice
nice quod suus aliquis alius hie et videre ac ut
to see the sort of developing for the
videre generis ad developing
linux platform i don't i'm assuming
Im 'posito quod non Linux catasta
we're talking soccer I don't know not
erant loquentes nescio Morbi neque
not American folk is it is it yeah they
American vulgares, non est hoc quod est yeah
kind of look like soccer tonight I think
Morbi elit nocte quadam puto
it would be like British football yes as
esset similis British eu est ita
opposed to well I mean the rest of the
atque id contra reliquos
world football as opposed to what's with
mundi eu est ut opponitur ei quod suus '
that a speaking of Miss for NATO I mean
Nata est enim qui non vult loqui de Miss
they actually hitting up the ball with
non autem actu hitting pila ex
their foot in real football that makes
In eu pede suo quod facit realem
sense see as opposed to this pointy
quod videatur contrarium est sensus huius acutis
thing that you have to cat looks like a
quae res vos have ut vultus amo a cattus
rugby ball is a little pointy gives what
Pila Rngby dat paulum acutis
camps well I'll tell you the QR code is
QR code castris quoque dicam quod
not dead and in fact may help save lives
immo mortua salute adiuvet
nice Mercedes Benz is adding QR codes to
QR codes ad Mercedes grata est addendo
help emergency workers save car crash
Auxilium operarios salvum emergency car fragore
victims black and white square bar codes
alba et nigra quadratum bar codicibus victimarum
are designed to help firefighters in the
quae ordinantur ad auxilium, in firefighters
paramedic critical information needed to
paramedic discrimine notitia opus est
save car crash victims the QR codes
nisi car fragore victimas et QR codes
direct smartphones to a web page showing
Suspendisse potenti Paginam directum ad ostensionem
how to cut into each type of vehicle to
quam ad interficiam in vehiculum inter se rationem
free its passengers the firm said it had
et dixit ei firmum libero vestibulum
waived the right to patent the in the
Patet autem esse in dextra vetera omittere
innovation so that others could use it
innovation ut alios uti possent
free of charge until now Daimler said if
usque modo gratis dicitur, si Daimler
a vehicle was damaged beyond recognition
Vehiculum immutatus reddebam
emergency workers might have to call in
opus fuerunt ut appellabant
its registration plate to obtain the
Proportio plate consequi
necessary details that could take extra
Details necessarium esset, ut extra accipere
time certainly good precious time a
tunc certe a bonis bonum tempus
press release said it informs about the
torcular release certiores de illa dixit:
location of the airbags the battery the
in altilium in in locus airbags
tanks electric cables high pressure
obterere electrica funem rumpite princeps pressura
cylinders and other components in the
et alia components in columpnis rotundis
case of hybrid models the location of
hybrid locum casus exempla monstrabit,
the additional batteries and
in eu gravida et additional
high-voltage cables too that's a neat
quod suus 'etiam a tersus-altum voltage funibus marinis
idea that is an excellent idea I was
Optimum est quod idea
looking at the photo and wondering how
vultus in photo quod admiratio quam
exactly this works that's actually the
prorsus ut suus 'vere in hoc operatur
the gas door like that where you refill
quia sicut gas ad ostium quo consumpta replere,
the diesel ok so it's easily excessive
facilius est enim ut urna pellentesque nimia
in there yeah which is kind of clever
memini enim est quaedam subtilis apud
I've always liked QR codes and we have
Ego autem semper probaverunt et QR codes
one here at the show to take out of our
hic nostri tollere ad spectaculum
mobile site I think that it's a great
mobile site ut puto suus 'a magnus
solution and this free right so might as
et hoc justum poteras solutio
well utilize it but cool to see that
tum utendum sit, sed quia frigus videre
they're using it for
est quia illi erant 'usura
like that well so I bring up the car
quod tam bene sicut et adduxero super currus
specs that'd be cool for like auto
vellem autem esse massa frigus nam simile Auto
mechanics will not be neat yeah they
Materiae non esse tersus quod yeah
said of having today you know you could
Dixit autem habens vobis: Nescio vos hodie poterat
have the shop manual on your on your
habet tabernam in vestri manual
computer or on your handheld device and
handheld fabrica quod nec computatrum tuum
like a how do you change the flying old
quasi volantem ad antiquum mutare quomodo vos
anger on the narrow if all that was
quod si ira angustias
listening if all that is listening you
Audiebant autem omnia quae audierat
know here's an opportunity for you to
hic quia est occasio te
tap into QR codes what do you say
ICTUS in QR codes Tu ergo quid dicis
greater yeah that would be neat a 13
memini enim maior esset XIII tersus
year old boy who was kidnapped in the
senem annos singulos, qui sunt in tollebant
Pakistani city of Karachi after being
Pakistani post urbem Karachi
lured into a meeting via Facebook has
inlecebra testimonii per Facebook habet
been rescued he is reportedly the son of
hoc est parem filius repositae fuerant
a senior customs official in the city
a senior in urbe publica consuetudines
police say that the criminal gang
in criminalibus cohors vigilum dicere
masquerade is an online gaming friend
erupit est amicus online forumque aleatoruml
and abducted him after arranging to meet
disponens ad eum rapuit
him last week the gang demanded $500,000
Ultima septimana ad eum cohors postulavit $ 500,000
ransom the boy's mother made an
factum est mater pueri quo ei propitier
emotional plea to other parents to
causa motus aliorum parentum
supervise their children's use of social
usu socialis invigilet et dentes filiorum obstupescunt
media saying this is my request to all
dicens omnibus instrumentis hoc est petitio
the parents to never let their children
numquam liberos parentibus
make friendship on facebook you know
Facebook te amicitiam
that's wise words like I mean making a
Verba sapientium sicut quod non sit appropriatio
friend on Facebook very very dangerous
Cornelius periculosum valde amicum
because you don't or any social media
aut si non facis, quia socialis instrumentis
platform you just don't know is I mean I
platform vos iustus non est, ut sit tibi
know people who have met folks on
plebs folks qui nesciunt in occurrit
Facebook they've gone on and getting
Questus et in Facebook non exieris
married lived happily ever after high
nupta umquam feliciter vixit, postquam altos
however my wife on icq yeah free msn
uxori autem de libera icq yeah msn
days but there's a lot of scary stuff
dies autem illic 'multus of supellectilem FORMIDULOSUS
right there too there isn't these days
ibi etiam non multis diebus
and here's the thing this lady says you
et hic est res haec dicit dominae vobis
know be don't let them make friends on
nec sciunt amici faciant
Facebook but what happens you mentioned
At verum quidem Facebook te nominatus
something to me before the show which is
qui ante me aliquid ad spectaculum
a little bit scary look what happens if
parum FORMIDULOSUS vultus aliquantulus, si quid accidit
somebody we've talked about fish we've
quis weve communicaverunt de et nos Ive 'piscis
been friends a long time we've talked
amicorum esse diu locuti sumus,
about phishing scams what happens if
Si fit de phishing scams
someone pretends to be somebody that you
quod aliquis fingit se esse aliquem
know I have had three friendship
amicitiae tres nosti
requests on facebook in the last couple
petitiones ad facebook in novissimis duobus
of weeks they go out and they take your
tolle quod tuum est et vade hebdomades sunt,
picture I had a Robbie Ferguson friend
Habui amicum pictura Robbie Tacitus
request we've been friends a long time
petitionem habuimus amicos diu
yeah if I and Andres copy Ferguson my
yeah et si mihi Andre effingo Tacitus
mom but they'd even copied some of your
sed youd 'vel aliquo mom copied tuae
you know the fact that you like pie okay
scis hoc quod pie tibi okay
some of your information from your bio
quidam notitia ex bio
they
quod
boro that too they bird your picture
et quod avis Boro ad imaginem tuam
flight at conchords reference and I'm
conchords fuga a me, et referiat
thinking you know why is Robbie sending
quid cogitas te mitto Robbie
me request I've just been reading some
Ego iustus peto mihi legendi sunt quidam
of his updates sure and then I went back
Et reversus de certo updates
to check to make sure that may be here
fac ut hic sisto
still fun i friended me on by i was
amet in me per ego ego esset etiam friended
gonna say by accident but even on
dicere 'agnus dei ab accidente, sed etiam in
purpose and then changed his mind but no
et deinde ad mentem vertit non nisi
he was still in my friend list so yeah
et ipse est amicus meus usque in album ut yeah
and i had it happen with another friend
quod accidit et amicum
Steve because I don't need much last
Steve tandem quod non opus multum
names but I've had three of them in the
Ego autem nomina quoque eorum per tres
last couple of weeks so be careful and I
et tandem duobus weeks et facient ea
get it to like so you're on Facebook and
ut eam tu similis ut in Facebook et
this person pops in and says you've got
et homo dicit haec pops in te surrexit
a friend request from and it could be it
illa petentibus et amicus esset
could be your wife it could be someone
quod uxor tua sit aliquis possit esse
real close to you could but if you're
Si autem verus prope es tu
not already friends with Robbie Ferguson
Tacitus Robbie iam amicorum
and you get that you're gonna say oh
O, et vos adepto ut diceret amet
click sure you know and then who knows
click certo novimus et qui te scit,
what here's the thing if they can friend
quid hic potest nisi rei familiaris
you so let's say this guy whoever it is
guy qui vobis ita lets 'narro hoc est,
and it's you know who is it right who is
et factum est et scitis iustum est qui
pretending to be me on Facebook Ads Eric
uelut ad me Facebook Ads Eric
kit as a friend because there's
quoniam amicus suus ornamentum
obviously a connection here and they can
manifesto autem hic et in nexu possunt
figure out that ok if I get them as a
instar sicco quam impetro illis quasi si ok
friend so now if you fell for that you
Si autem exierit sodali
accepted that what happens is I get
ut non sit, quod accepit quid accidit
access to your friend list exactly so
ita prorsus aditus ad amicum tuum album
now I can go out and I can say okay also
nunc etiam bene dicere non possum, et egredietur
hahaha Hilary Rumble Rachel shoe Abigail
Hilarius in Matth hahaha murmure Rachel calceamentum Abigail Carmelitide
Smith all of these people plus everyone
Cicero his omnibus plus omnibus
else laughter all the young women
reliqua omnia puellae risus
although people who work for the show
qui ostendunt opus quidem
old right because they're connected to
Lorem olim coniungebatur rectum
you now that we're friends i can see
ut sis amicus videre possum tibi
their files very very easily so by
ita facillime impetiti ipsum
fretted by you accidentally friending
rapto per accidens friending
that fake friend you've opened it up for
fictus amicus pro se aperiens
all your other friends to be compromised
alii amici decipi
as well and who knows how many peers a
quis enim scit quot aeque pares
12 year old 13 year old boy who was
XII XIII annos singulos annos natus erat, qui senem
kidnapped yeah on account of this stuff
Hostes ob ista memini
with a ransom and it you know thank God
Gratias ago Deo, quod tu scis cum quo redempti dimitteremur
that he's okay that's serious stuff so
ut suus 'okay ut' gravis et supellectilem
we need to be a careful folks really and
nobis necesse est esse vere ac diligenter ostendere folks
how many people actually do know all
quam multi norunt esse omnibus
their friends I mean I've accepted
Ego accepit mean ego suos
friends request because well being a
tum quia cum amicis petentibus
musician quite off y'all send out hey
Emitte Domine musico plane insanus inmunibus
I've got a gig man talk moans this
Ego cisiis pervolavit possedi hominem hunc quasi tibiae resonabit Disputatio
friday night if anybody's in the area um
Nocte si um quemque regionis
but i'll send that sort of thing i'm
sed illius generis est vis eum mittere sum
sending the people who aren't maybe my
num quid me dimitteret populum
besties sure what uh but then you get
sed tunc certus vos adepto besties quod uh
requests and i'm thinking
petitiones et cogito
I don't know if I even know this person
Nescio si quidem sciunt hunc hominem
right but you know if its name you know
sed dextera scitis nomen ejus, si nosti
it's a little thing I recognize that
suus 'a parum est tibi quod agnoscis
name maybe it's somebody that I know
maybe suus 'Scio, quod quis nomen eius
they are friends with all these other
Haec sunt omnes amici
people that I know exact because they
qui prorsus nesciunt quam quod ego
already fell for it all right my
nam prius omnia mea cecidi
goodness to mess what I takes care of
quod bonitas et cibum accipit curam
stuff yeah okay california teen has come
yeah supellectilem bene teen venit california
up with a way to save you from a dead
ut eruaris de mortuo cum
phone in just 20 seconds flat wow that's
In phone tantum XX minutes flat quod wow
impressive eesha khare an 18 year old
XVIII anno, senex an infigo eesha khare
high school student has put her
alta schola discipulo quem posuit illam
impressive chemistry knowledge to work
cognitio operis liber dignitas
by inventing an energy storage device
fingendo repono fabrica industria
that can charge a cell phone in 20 to 30
cell phone in in XX ad XXX, qui possit arguere
seconds she says that her cell phone
haec dicit illi cell phone seconds
battery always dies which led her to
altilium moritur semper ad illam quae ducitur
work on the supercapacitor the device
in opus ad supercapacitor fabrica
which lets you store lots of energy in a
quae patitur multis thesaurizas in virtute
tiny space and hold it for a long time
exiguum locum teneat diu
has about 10 times the number of charge
fere X temporibus crimen est numerus
cycles than a conventional rechargeable
cycles rechargeable eu quam conventional
battery Wow the eighteen-year-old summed
Wow altilium circumactis decem et octo annos summa
up her invention for us lay folk as
invention eam est ponere pro nobis, ut vulgares
follows to improve supercapacitor and
et sequitur ut amplio supercapacitor
energy tense I can't even say it to
non possum dicere ad tempus et navitas
improve a supercapacitor energy density
densitate et amplio navitas supercapacitor
I designed synthesized and characterized
Et ego disposuerat summatim perstringitur characterised
a novel course shown nanorod electrode
novum sane ostensum est nanorod electrode
with a hydrogenated TI 0 2 core and
cum hydrogenated II ti 0 et core
Pollyanna line shell well I'm glad she
Pollyanna tam lineam testam gaudeo illa
dumped it up for us a whole like thank
ut totum illud nostrum gratias rasurae
you now she's just showing off but it's
vos autem illa, sed tantum ad ostentationem suus '
ironic because I have four years you
quatuor annis, aderunt autem habeo tui
remember I've been saying this year I
Ego memini me hoc anno est dicens
said if only someone would improve super
dicitur aliquis esse meliorem, si modo Super
capacity energy density by designing
density facultatem industria malitiosis
synthesizing characterizing a novel
characterizing summatim referendo ad usum eorum
course shell nanorod electrode with a
Nempe cum testa nanorod Electrode
hydrogenated tio2 core and polyaniline
hydrogenated tio2 polyaniline et core
shell and here soon as I had a nickel
hic primum testa habui Nickel
for every time I heard you say that I
omne tempus quod ego audivi de te,
know I know penniless I should have
Scio enim quia cohors inanis aptis me
hadn't had the idea folks I should have
rationem habuisset sem haberem
patented the idea so I'm saying why
dicentes quod ideam patented et ego
didn't I third time that's happened to
nonne tertio manifestatus acciderit
me this why didn't I think of that yeah
memini me cogitare cur non
and you know what
et quid
she's been awarded the Intel foundation
consideratum in illa sunt fundamenta Intel
young scientist award and 50,000
50,000, et puer physicus award
smackeroos I'm real yeah so I'd be happy
smackeroos sum ego ut beati sint vera yeah
to good on you Asia yeah all right get
bonum tibi est ad adepto rectum omnium Asiae yeah
the full story as a category 5 TV /
plenam historia ut genus TV V /
newsroom the category 5 TV news room is
V locus est genus NEWSROOM TV News
researched by roy w Nash with
Roy investigentur ex Nash in Latin
contributions by our community of
in conventu nostro de contributions
viewers if you have a news story you
si autem habes nuntium fabulam viewers
think is worthy of on-air mention email
in aere, videtur esse dignum mention inscriptio
newsroom at category 5 TV for that
V newsroom genus in quod TV
category 5 TV needs from i am dr. spa
V genus TV necessaria sunt Ego sagittis bibendum erat. Spa
i'm eric kid easily confused by his
Maecenas hedum per i facile confundi
Lincoln few the ears yeah well you know
Pauci sciunt bene memini aures Lincolniensis
hey do you hear about the world's
heus tu exaudi de mundi
largest LEGO model actually I want to go
volo ut lego maximum exemplum actually
back to the super capacitor charge rod
Super custodiam capacitor ad baculum
did a thing I'm seem that much that much
Videtur quod aliquid Im 'non ut nimis
power in a tiny little space what kind
Qualem potestatem parvo spatio
of evil could we Oh boys this for I'm
poterat enim est malum hoc, o pueri sum
not risking weapons-grade naquadah in
meumque obieci armis, non per gradus naquadah
like pill form danger Will Robinson how
sicut forma periculi lobortis quam Cicero
can I make him I I did see a comment
Ego possum facere me ipsum did animadverto a comment
there in the chat room what is this
quis est iste locus enim in chat
dilithium which would be a fantastic
dilithium esset phantasticam
idea maybe we could power intergalactic
potuit fortasse ratio potentiae intergalactic
space ships with this time a game it was
hoc ipsum erat navium spatium
wondering about when somebody he won't
miratus quis esset de quo non
he wait until you figure out how to do
Donec ut instar sicco quomodo
it with a potato well so she's built the
Capsicum annuum et cum illa ita quoque qui fabricavit illam
ability to charge a cell phone in 30
arguere facultatem a cell phone in XXX
seconds flat now if 20 seconds 10
XX seconds X seconds plana nunc
seconds flat if ever regret it if only
si modo semper paenitet, si plana seconds
Apple would now take that technology and
Lacus nunc accipere ut technology quod
make it so that their phones last for
ita quod durabit luctus et
longer than 20 seconds before it started
diutius quam XX minutes ante coepi
that it's only got twenty percent
Quod suus 'tantum got viginti percent
battery life then we'd be somewhere then
altilium vitae, tunc ergo volumus esse possit
we'd be so take that no seriously the
ita ut nullus serio sistere
the largest LEGO model ever created did
maxima Lego semper exemplar creatum est fecit
you hear about this this is fantastic uh
tu exaudi de hoc fantastic est uh
you need to get onto google take a look
Vos postulo ut Google take a vultus onto
at it but they have created a life-size
sed ad ea quae creata est a vita-amplitudo
you want to see pictures of this thing
hanc rem vos volo video vidi imaginibus
and I could
et non poterat
the month but you just get on to the
in mense autem vos iustus adepto ad in
your favorite search engine and do a
consectetuer adipiscing quaero engine et in vobis
quick search for the largest Lego
quick search for maxima Lego
structure in the news and you'll see it
in structuram et nuntium youll 'animadverto suus
but they've created a life-size like a
sed youve 'partum a vita-amplitudo tamquam
real true scale model the size of the
ipsa vera scale exemplar magnitudinem
set of the x-wing fighter from star wall
X super murum ala perpetrarat de stella
so they're just one of these things I
ut illi iustus unus horum sum
was up for ages 12 it up or oh boy okay
et ascendit in saecula saeculorum ascendit nec O pueri XII ut bene
that in the back of 5.3 million pieces
ut tergum 5.3 million pieces
of Lego the thing way am I am so close
Lego in rem tam prope ego sum via
and there's one missing and a collapse
nec deest unus atque concidere
that would be crazy your wife walks in
ut esset uxor tua ambulat in rabidus
and locks it with the door she would too
capillos ex hoc quoque esset atque ipsa ianua
because it's very big and the door would
Magna enim et fores
be right up against it 5.3 million
ut ius illud adversus eum 5.3 million
pieces this thing is huge it was
Hoc est enim quod esset ingens pieces
unveiled at Times Square and last
Times Square, et tandem ad unveiled
Thursday and just as spectacular marvel
Iovis et iustum est spectacular mirabile
of the company that Lego that put this
Lego quod in hoc comitatu
thing together like hundreds of
est sicut unum centum
thousands of man-hours it's crazy and
et suus 'rabidus horas, milia hominum
it's all because they've got this Yoda
Ive 'got hoc actum, quod Yoda
chronicles starting up in the cartoon
incipiens a viverra in fastos
network I think it starts tomorrow
network puto incipit cras
actually so really really neat kind of
et ex re ipsa vere tersus
guerilla marketing publicity stunt to
guerilla in venalicium vulgaret INCREMENTUM
pull something like that that's kind of
quasi aliquid trahere, quod id genus
crazy indeed but similarly okay so I'm
bene quidem eodem modo ut insanus, sed Im '
like okay we'll all this buzz around
si tibi placet ut bene nobis omnibus stridore vocales circa hanc
Star Wars what's that I mean you're just
Star Wars Quid quod intelliguntur tu iustus
trying to get your you know I mean what
trying impetro vestri ego novi autem quod sit
are they doing really I mean start
rem faciunt non sit incipere
fractures in theater logs and star wars
omnia ossa stella bellorum theatrum
for the last two older yeah but Star
in novissimis duo senior, sed stella yeah
Trek is in the theater you yourself Eric
Trek in theatro ipsa Eric
kid is wearing a Star Trek shirt I mean
hedum in frusta concerperet est circumdatio de Star Trek ut sit shirt
this has got to be huge folks so it is
Hoc habet esse folks tam ingens est,
like your lover so what's happening with
quod amans sic fit similis tui est
Star Trek right so okay if they're doing
Bene igitur feceris, si recte agant Ave
all this kind of stuff with Star Wars I
omnia vasa haec et cum Star Wars
mean they've got to be doing something
quid sibi volunt facere ut Ive 'got
with Star Trek check out new starship
Ave per novum Lorem starship
calm new star ship calm this is so
novam stellam leniret navem ita cessabit
exciting for TNG fans a group of fans
TNG fans de coetus fans est ut excitando
did a Kickstarter they raised something
fecit et erexit se aliquid Kickstarter
like four times as much money as they
ut ipsi argento quadruplum
needed they have actually obtained the
necesse est quod in effectu percepit
original will the the 1997 Star Trek
qui autem originale MCMXCVII de Star Trek
Enterprise d ncc-1701 d bridge
A re, ncc a ponte MDCCI
I used you know my brother used to watch
Ego autem quia frater meus ad vigilate
that show back mrs. yes he sounds help
Quia, ut ostenderet retro. et quod sic sonat Auxilium
let even kinetics tease no we're talking
et non erant loquentes et ludere equilibrium
90s okay okay oh that show okay but I
O spectaculum illud 90s okay okay okay, sed non
remember oh sorry I posen yeah the
O ego memini me paenitet et posen yeah
elevator in all his friends sitting oh I
elevator in omnes amici eius sedebat me O
feel like I'm going to fall all right
sentio amo Im 'iens ut iure cadere universa
but check this out folks new starship
sed hoc fit novus reprehendo starship
com you can find out more about the
.com potes reperire ex pluribus de
project find out about who is supporting
invenies qui de project et sustentans
at what they're doing where they're
quid ibi tu discis
going to be they're gonna be in Texas
iens futurus es agnus dei esse non Texas
they're going to be I believe in
ipsi erant 'iens ut fiat in me
California Las Vegas yeah and Pasadena
California Las Vegas yeah, et Pasadena
as well they're in long note they were
nimium diu nota essent ipsi quoque in
in Long Beach they're actually in
Litus Longum est in actu quod tu
Houston Texas no just left they just
Houston, Texas iustum non dereliquit iusta sunt
love comic comic their way yeah they're
Sic yeah ut sis in amore comici comici
back in houston texas in august but
In Houston in Texas, sed revertar in augustam
anyway what they're doing is they're
est quod usquam discis ut sis
actually rebuilding from the original
actually ab originali quam aedificant extruentes
will from the set pieces that were
erant autem qui a paro pieces
created after the destruction of the
post exitium creata est
enterprise so here are the the set
hic ergo res sunt
pieces as they obtained them some of
et particulas quas quisque adeptus quidam eorum
them are still in pretty good shape and
eorum qui adhuc in pulchra figura, et bonum
they're actually recreating got it like
ipsi erant 'actu got simile recreans
that you would shut it all right just
quia iustus claudat satin
stop just stop so they're recreating the
et illi erant 'iustus nolite prohibere recreans
set and they're gonna you can rent it to
posuit et tradidit eam custodibus ut possis amet
I mean photo booth whatever whole show
Dico quod totum spectaculum photo umbraculum
rental your weddin get married on the
adepto vestri matrimonium per rentalis weddin
Starship Enterprise bridge imagine that
Starship pontem imaginari non Enterprise
but they've got all the part they've got
habeo sed quod habeo omni parte
the ceiling they've got the walls
moenia et tecta teneo
they've got the seats they've got penny
Ive 'got sedes ad assem Heu
penny penny I think we should buy this
assem assem puto emere oportet quod
thing for this for the next category 5
hoc enim aliquid in altera genus V
set so please send in your donations we
mitte nos in eleemosynis tarn
need lots of cash it's gonna cost us
Nos postulo lots of cash suus 'agnus dei cost
like two hundred thousand dollars what
Sicut enim ducenta milia pupa
these guys are actually doing it so find
haec guys sunt faciens ea et invenietis actually
out more on their website for that kind
magis in genere website
of money you get through up for video
pecunia ut per eum ad vos video
okay or or Kenya does it even exists new
Kenya est etiam existit aut novum aut bene
starship com that is your Trek news for
starship culpa est, quod per nuntium Trek
tonight awesome i'm excited to see that
Sum excitatur ad hoc terribilis hac nocte
all right
omnibus fas
hey we've got time for a couple viewer
Comperto heu nunc in duobus videntium
questions thank you so much for sending
gratias ago tibi, quia multum quaestiones et mittens
those in to us category 5 TV is our
V ad eorum TV genus noster nobis
website email us live at category 5 TV
Vivamus at genus website email V TV
to get your questions in Eric what do
ut quid rogationibus tuis in Eric
you got for me there's one from a while
te obtinuit me ab dum illic '
back I am evening Robbie hope you and
Spero te et Robbie reversus sum ad vesperam
your family are well who's this this is
tua sunt bene quis est hic
from scooty Duke 42 from Bolton quarter
ab eadem parte ex XLII scooty ducis
dork England will call them scooty duck
vocant illas in Anglia dork scooty anatis
but yes okay maybe it'll do you glad
ita maybe okay, sed quod sic faciam vobis
sounds cool no the Akron keeps changing
Antiquariat Posoniensis, altum frigus et servat mutantur nihil
yeah okay so even in the Robbie a hope
tam bene memini Robbie in spem
you and your family are well vairocina
tu et domus tua valetis vairocina
review for an open source alternative to
an open source alternative ut ad review
skype called jitsi yeah as Jay ITSI
Song in circo dicitur jitsi yeah ITSI
looks really good if you already know
Si iam nostis spectat vere bonum,
about apologies but might be worth a
dignum est ut sit de non paenitemus
look on a show in the future thanks
ostendit futura et aspiciat in gratiarum actione
again to you and the gang I guess I'm
EGO coniecto Im 'cohors et iterum ad vos
gang absolutely for the great channel
omnino enim magna cohors channel
yours sincerely Oh Scott Jones oh hey
Scott heu heu O sincere vestrum Jones
Scott let's go out cheers man um okay
Scott eamus exire iubentium homo bene um
yeah jitsi is is definitely an
yeah est certus est jitsi
up-and-coming kind of you know secure
venientes autem et quales tu securum,
video calls ala kind of skype video i
video vocat ala ex circo ego video
think what would be exciting is it yeah
Yeah esset quanta est suscipit
if this actually caught on and people
si omnino homines capiuntur
started using it then awesome I think we
Tunc coepi usura is ut puto horribilis
should maybe try it out the top why
Quod si forte probas illum summum
don't we try to I think the tough thing
dura res non arbitror conamur
here Scott is that jitsi is coming up
Scott est hic est qui venit jitsi
against Microsoft skype is huge google
Microsoft est ingens in circo Google
video and google talk and all those
Disputatio Google video, et omne quod illi,
everything is huge everything is
omnia enim quae ingens est,
established i guess you'd say apparently
statutum ego coniecto videtur quod dicere velis
lets you connect to facebook google doc
Google doc lets vos iungo to del.icio.us
well for instant messaging for sure yeah
tum certe per quantitatem yeah
but you think about who they would be
Sed cogitare essent
competing for users against there are so
competing quia non ita sunt contra users
many people on skype who would have no
Multi homines, qui non habent in circo
reason to switch to to jitsi unless
ideo ad artem non jitsi
you're really into you know if you want
Si tu scis rem in te
to be involved in a great project so I'm
ita Im 'opus grande quemquam esse minus deditum
excited to see where it might works on
Is ubi operatur concitatae
any of us I believe so yeah yeah check
nec nobis sic credere me reprehendo yeah yeah
it out as jitsi org anyways if you want
ita ut sis anyways jitsi org
to take a quick boo at what jitsi is
in boo quod sit velox ad jitsi
open source video
aperta fonte video
yo calls chat all that kind of stuff so
Curabitur io dico quod hoc genus effercio
kind of other charges involved with this
hoc genus cetera quorum
well if you want to make phone calls I'm
Bene, si me vis facere phone vocat
sure there are like SI p kind of stuff
Si fideles sunt quasi quaedam p supellectilem
but as far as using general usage over
sed quod usque communis usus per usura
your internet connection there wouldn't
Nolo enim vestra conexio
be any charges I'm not even sure yeah
Im 'non certus esse criminibus yeah
i'm i'm pretty sure it does support SI p
Im 'pulchellus certus ut Im' non SI p firmamentum
but you can check it out on their
potes in look
website at sea org thanks for the
Signum gratiam in mari website
comment Scott and I think if people
Et puto, si populus comment Scott
adopt it and you know I hope that that
Spero autem quod cognoscetis vos amplector
we're able to see the market open up a
aperire foro videre potuit enim sumus
little bit more because right now it's
modicum aliquantulus magis quia nunc suus '
really kind of all skype it's KP out
ex omni genere KP vere est skype
there mhm alright this is from Greg hey
licet haec est mHM heus ab Greg
Greg from Michigan USA go michigan and
USA ad Michigan et Michigan ab Greg
happy memorial day yesterday d yeah okay
felicem memoriam hesterno die d bene yeah
uh Greg says thanks for addressing my
tibi gratias ago pro me dicit Greg uh addressing
question about benchmarks last week you
benchmarks de quaestione ultima septimana vobis
become that may not actually been last
facti sunt ut non fuerit ultimum actually
week that was several weeks ago but ubcd
quae fuit ante aliquot hebdomades septem, sed ubcd
may not be organized as well as I'd like
Volo etiam quod non potest celebratio
but it does the job ultimate boot CD I
sed hoc facit ultimum officium mihi tabernus CD
okay that's what I thought yeah it's
suus 'okay ut' quod cogitavi yeah
been a few weeks now but yeah yeah I
sed pauci weeks nunc et fuerit yeah yeah
think that we saw it's kind of hard to
videtur durum genus vidimus
find your way around but once you get in
dirigas vias tuas omnique circa nisi semel in vos adepto
and you figure out where you're going it
et vos instar sicco qua vos erant 'iens ut
works really really well really
vere vere vere bene operatur
comprehensive suite of tools so took
et tulit de instrumenta comprehensive suite
your advice and installed point linux on
et consilium iam installed in vestri Linux
more my old machines you're right it
plus ea dextera mea sis machinis
seems more responsive than some of the
dociles magis quam de
more popular distro scope there are you
illic es magis vulgaris distraho scope
glad to hear it so good to know that
aveo audire, quae est scire illud bonum
it's running well on some of those older
Bene suus 'currit in quidam illorum maior
machines running great on our system
currit ratio machinarum ingenti nobis
here point linux up on my screen that's
hic designandum Linux meum in screen ut '
what we're using very cool check it out
quid erant 'usura reprehendo is sicco valde frigus
alright well yours isn't from coal Carl
licet etiam ex tua est calculus Carl
Cunningham hey Carl okay okay okay we've
Carl okay okay okay si youve 'heus Cunningham
been through this after me hi Robbie my
Hi post me, hoc est in meo: Robbie
wife and I cracked up when you were
et uxor ejus vastitatem dum
pronounced again joking about our
Rursumque locutus iocus circa
username okay okay did I get it wrong we
nomen usoris okay okay fecisti mihi iniuriam non adepto eam
don't know as it turns out heck is both
tum fit quod non est diaboli
of our initials so we grabbed the domain
Ita nostri tenuerunt dominico initial
from cat kept calm okay internationally
a cattus tenentur cessabit bene internationally
ambiguous as
ut ambigua disserentem
whose initials come first I used the
primus veni ego in quorum primae litterae
username keck keck keck just for fun
Keck username Keck Keck iustus pro fun
sometimes we really enjoyed your take on
nunc autem vobis vere fruendum suscipiunt
it by the way found your site about a
ita per viam inveni de vobis locum
month ago and loved the show you have
et dilexit mensis abhinc ostendo vobis
been using Linux 14 years now almost
XIV annos iam prope uti Linux
exclusively so that's Carl and Cathy
et sic quod solum Carl Cathy
Carlin candy middle initials are e i
Media sunt ei initial tempor carlin
would guess we got some Carla Hathi
Carl coniecto nos got ut quidam Hathi
Cunningham within e in the middle okay
E media inter Dolosus purus
so much for tuning in Carlin Cathy and
Cathy et tuning enim in tanta Carlin
nice to have you joining us all right
Recte fecisti veniendo tincidunt
well Wow here's one from Bucharest
Wow huc suus 'etiam ab Bucarest
Romania awesome what software are you
Romania terribilis software, quod estis vos
using for URL shortening yes in cat5 TV
in URL quod sic correptio apud usura TV CAT5
yeah somebody sometimes you know I say
quis nunc dico vobis quia yeah
go to cap 5 TV / whatever because that's
V cap ad TV / id quidquid est, quod
our URL shown right and when I do that
URL nobis ostensum est, et cum recte facere
it actually it's not category 5 TV it's
V TV suus 'non genus esse in actu,
cat five dot TV and it puts you on to
TV et dat quinque cattus ut regere possis
whatever site that we like to so the way
Quod si velimus locum tali modo
that we do that is a program called URLs
ut id quod est a progressio dicitur delata
and it spelled y.o.u RLS and it's
et integer est, et te RLS
brilliant it allows you to create your
præclarus sino vos ut creare vestri
own kind of like bit ly or tinyurl
quasi propria quaedam et frenum iter tinyurl
service so you register a short URL and
ut subcriptio muneris brevi et URL
then you can use it all you want and if
tunc vos can utor et, si omnes vos volo
you wanted to you could pardon me you
tu velles ignoscere posse
could set it up to be an actual public
posse esse in re publica et posuit eum
server that people could submit their
Servo quod poterat committere
own URLs through it has a good API it's
illud est per se bonum delata est API
connected to our WordPress blogs and
pertinet ad WordPress blogs
automatically generates short URLs for
automatare nobis delata in brevi
Twitter for us and all that kind of
Nos talem et Twitter
stuff so it's pretty brilliant works
ita praeclara opera satis domi
very very well y ou URL s is the is the
URL s seu etiam ipsius y ipsum esse est
name of it and i'll post a link for you
Ego ibo post te: et nomen loci illius, vinculum
in the show notes of episode number 297
episode in ex numero ostendunt notas CCXCVII
and those dragos a website jira question
et Dragoş JIRA quaestionem a website
all right before we move on tonight's
ius est prius moto nocte
show is brought to you in part by net
ostende te fit partim rete
talk and now they've got unlimited text
et iam summa textu dicere theyve 'got
messaging you can eliminate the need for
Vos can eliminate ad opus messaging
a wireless text plan from your cell
in wireless illud tuum consilium, a cellula
phone provider upgrade your nettalk duo
Duo provisor upgrade vestri phone nettalk
account with the net talk text plan for
ideo cum textu consilium rete Disputatio
the cost of a couple of cups of coffee a
sumptus autem de duobus pocula capulus
month you're going to receive unlimited
mense vos erant 'iens accipere infinita,
texting throughout the US and canada
texting in Canada et US
check out cap five dot TV / phone and
Lorem cap quinque dat TV / Phone et
saving money today there you have it
quod hodie peculi tibi
there's one of our short URLs cat5 TV /
illic 'unus ex nobis delata nostra brevis CAT5 TV /
phone just show you how it works also
phone sicut ostendam vobis etiam quomodo operatur
big news from netflix over the past
nuntium de magnum super praeteritum Netflix
couple of weeks is that the Bluths are
quod est duobus weeks es Bluths
back ah Arrested Development the next
altera ah, comprehensus retro Development
season is now available all 15 episodes
XV omni tempore praesto est nunc online
you don't have to wait for them they're
erant quos non expectat
on netflix right now and I'd like to
a Netflix et nunc ego amo
give you all 15 episodes absolutely free
XV omnino liberum online dabo vobis omnia
all you have to do is go over to cat
omne enim quod faciunt, ut vadam ad feles
five dot TV / Netflix you're going to
quinque dat TV / Netflix vos erant 'iens
get your one month free trial that's
ut tuum iudicium liberum mense uno ut '
plenty of time to watch the Bluths and
otii et contemplare Bluths
all of their silly antics on the final
Ridiculum omnibus motibus eorum in finalem
season of Arrested Development cat five
arreptus ipsum felis quinque anni
dot TV / netflix they'll give you a free
dat TV / dabo tibi libera non Netflix
one month trial of netflix no strings
una mensis iudicium de Netflix nec tendere chordas
attached you can cancel it at any time
inrita possis aliquando coniuncta
and if you decide to keep going it's
Si volueris eam verumtamen
only eight bucks a month good deal hmm
octo tantum illos leones, quos mensem multum hmm
that was only 799 sorry of course we've
quod sane paenitet nos Ive 'tantum DCCXCIX
eliminated the and eliminated the penny
et eliminated per assem et eliminated
area yeah so even still alright what
yeah, quae regio est usque adhuc alright
else we have a question here from Danny
aliud habemus hic quaestio de O
Harbor Danny Harbor Robbie hey how to
O heus quam ad portum portum Robbie
program to get the following working and
progressio ut et Contra curiositatem studen
point Linux alright not play rented
licet non ludere punctum locavit Linux
Google movies in Linux google is showing
Google google ostendit movies in Linux
the phone right boon to and linux OS
Linux phone et rectam OS in boon
users must also install the hal module
users oportet install laxo moduli
drm flashing greener yep h al HAL flash
DRM corusco semper viridius yep h al HAL mico
reader for drm movies requires the
DRM postulat pro movies ad lectorem
hardware abstraction layer in linux ok
Linux hardware abstrahatur in algarum ok
because they're just not good enough
quia non satis est iustus
Adobe's falling behind plain and simple
Adobe lapsus tergum in meras et simplicis rimantur
and well people are why are people still
quae sunt adhuc et cur
using Adobe I don't know and we're
Adobe et per nescio sumus
streaming with Adobe Flash it's
cum effusis Adobe Flash est
frustrating as anything but when they're
sed quid est frustrating cum tu
behind and that so that what do they do
idque secundum quod faciunt
they say oh just install how well just
qui dicunt venias iustus install bene quam justo
take your computer that's brand new and
tolle quod tuum novam et computatrum
bleeding edge and stick something on it
sanguinem in ore gladii, et quod inhaero in ea
that's obsolete and deprecated and that
et quod autem antiquatur et Deprecated
will make are obsolete deprecated
deprecatus est autem antiquatur faciam
software work for you so but it will
vos autem non sic sed opus software
work if we if we wanted to all you need
Si enim non operatur nisi volens omnibus indigetis
to do is install how HAL on your linux
hoc facere est ut install vestri Linux HAL
computer what I've done is I've created
quid factum est, computatrum Ego Ego creata est
a a short link for you cat five dot TV
cat as short link quinque dat tibi TV
here it is again eh al so how flas h-how
hic autem iterum ut quam EH flas h al-quam
flash enter looks like huh flush
Suspendisse similis intrare facies huh
well it's how that's why i said okay
quid suus 'okay ut' quare etiam dicitur i
sudo apt-get install how it's as simple
ut install quam impetro suus 'simplex sudo oris sui,
as that if you're on debian type s you
Si vestri 's id quod ad vestrum genus debian
not sudo and then hit enter and then
et tunc ledo tunc intrant, et non sudo
just type apt-get install house so
Iustus typus ut install domum ut bene,
that's what you need is how then you
Tu ergo quid est hoc quod debes
just need to follow these really really
Iustus sequitur has vere postulo realiter
quick directions I mean this is telling
hic ostendit partes facile intelligo
you to do it that's kind of dangerous i
Ego tibi illud genus anceps
don't think i would suggest that you do
non puto esse ego suadeant quod tu facis
it this way what I would suggest instead
sic ea, quae vellem suadeant loco
just for safety's sake go to your home
ut propter salutem vade in domum tuam
folder hit ctrl L so that you activate
eu, ita fiat ut folder ledo Ctrl
the location and just go to that dot
qui dat locum, ut vadam, et iustus
adobe folder dot Adobe I don't want you
Adobe dat folder Adobe nolo vos
to run this command that doesn't RF
ut run is to order, quod non M.
because that's just too dangerous go
quia periculosum nimis est ire
into flash player delete everything ok
omnia delete mico ludio ludius in ok
that's your asset cash right click on it
quod tuum cash iustum dignissim click in ea
delete it that's going to accomplish
efficere ut delete deferretur
what they're telling you to do but with
sed tu sis qui loquaris ad id quod facere
this command that they're giving you if
Si dicas quod praecipio tibi
you accidentally miss type something
genus pressisti accidens deesset aliquid,
you're going to destroy your system so
ratio ut vos erant 'iens ut te perdere
we're going to forget about that all you
erant 'iens ut obliviscatur de omnibus quae te
want to do is just install how and then
quanta est vis ut faciam tibi sicut et tunc install
use Nautilus or whatever your favorite
Nautio sive uti ventus
you know my computer is go into the dot
scis ut meus computer est in puncto
adobe folder and delete everything from
Adobe et delere omnia a folder
there make it fair enough once you've
satis est pulchra est facere semel youve
done that row you're gonna be able to
fieri poterit ordine tu amet
watch drm video there you go it's gonna
illud video amet drm Grat vigilate
work please let us know if that worked
nos scimus placere si opus sit laboraverunt
for you ok man we have another one here
hic est aliquis alius homo si est ok
from Scotty duckers got he Duke 42 come
XLII de futuro duci esset nactus Caledoni duckers
on Scott we know his name hey hey Scott
Scott heu heu nomen ejus super nos scimus Scott
evening Robbie and Eric get caught up
Robbie adepto deprensus et factum est vespere usque Eric
with episode 2 95 great show on Apache
in Episode II XCV spectaculum magnum in Apache
thanks last time you were here yeah that
nunc tandem ago tibi quia hic yeah
is lost I'm just glad you enjoyed that
non fruendum, ut amissa vobis laetus ego sum,
lots of people sending in emails and
et fuere qui in sortem mittentes
communicating with us about how much
communicando cum quanta circa nos:
they enjoyed that show which is very
ostendens quod valde delectabantur
very cool we don't often get into server
frigus non nimis saepe adepto servo in
administration I was happy about that I
ut essem beatus circa administrationem
have a message to relay for to you from
habent enim ad CURSUS PUBLICI ad te
last week Robert Kazinsky Oh Robert our
Ultima septimana Robert Robert noster O Kazinsky
good friend Robert he said look Eric I'm
bonus amicus Robert dixit ecce ego sum Eric
gonna Robert connect all it's in my own
Robert suus 'agnus dei in se coniungere omnia,
words are you gonna paraphrase some
es agnus dei aliquibus verbis informatione
video someone is eloquent is robert
video autem Disertissime enim aliquis Robert
you're gonna paraphrase am yeah okay
es agnus dei bene yeah am come,
okay Eric can I can I do the accent I
Eric ego possum bene possum facere, disertus,
don't I don't think I could
nec possem non puto
don't say good day night okay I won't
Non dico autem non in die enim bona non bene noctem
ever do that I'm saying so because if
dicens ita, quod, si Im 'umquam hoc faciunt
you do you sound like a tourist accent
Tu es quasi accentu urbis
that was Robert it was that wasn't it
qui fuit Robert, quae erat et non est
particularly good as ya don't see no I
ut mihi videatur non bonae ya
can't do Australian accent I can make it
Australian accentus illud non poteris facere non possum
the only way I can get an Australian
non possum solus modus impetro in Australia
accent this is all he is to say there
hoc est dicere non est accentus
you go then it all of a sudden turns
alternis igitur tu repente
what was that you know like the good I
Quod factum scis quia amo te bonum
might see I can do that why is that I'm
ut videret quid ego possum illam
not late again Robert said something
Non dicitur aliquid nuper adhuc Robert
like if you say g'day mate one more time
ut si quis dicat tempus mate g'day
he's gonna come and smash up your
suus 'agnus dei vestri est, et venerunt, et confringes statuas
equally so whoa he knows he knows about
Heus sciens aeque sciat
us in Canada I didn't know any we do all
Ego nesciebam quid faciemus omne nos in Canada,
live in Italy just like that here you
quia sicut in Italia habito huc
know what Robbie just installed the
quid tantum installed in Robbie
couple cedar out host in the backyard
de medulla cedri in diam duobus exercitum
last week it's great yes ok one more
Ultima septimana unum suus 'ok quod sic magnus
weird one from dirt all regard cooking
de humo omne fatum ex decoctione
hi Robbie I've been using Linux for a
Hi sunt Robbie Ego uti Linux pro
little while now and love the free in
modicum nunc et in amant liberos
big letters dumb it gives you because of
quia dat litteris mutum
that my girlfriend is now interested in
Nunc interested in est quod amica mea
dual booting with MS
cum duplici MS patuissent
but he lives 80 miles away from me and
sed et ex duobus milibus LXXX
solving simple problems over the phone
solvendo simplex problems per telephonum
as a pain you're talking about could you
sicut dolor es de potest vos
show me how to remote desktops so that I
Quam procul ut ostenderes mihi desktops
can possibly help with problems she is
potest auxilium ad difficultates est,
reflective of computers right sorry
reflective ius paenitet of computers
we're smart mater moves around a program
non nimium captiosus mater movet circa programma
on this amazing show just love it tell
in hoc amore est mirabile spectaculum modo dicere
you Mike our hope to send a card soon to
Suspendisse non cito spem mittere pecto
you guys you'd love to receive the card
amabis guys ad card
from you thank you girl forgive my
gratias ago tibi, puella bona uenia tua te
co-host here he's fired okay teamviewer
et ignem huc exercitum cooperatores suus 'okay teamviewer
coming up taking my celery would know
venit usque valefaciens apium ut sciam
you can eat your celery artillery
te potest manducare apium arma tua
teamviewer.com all right there you go
Grat recte teamviewer.com
it's free to use for you and your
potest usurpari suus 'vestri et vos
girlfriend okay I know the music stopped
et stetit puella bene scio musicae
but there it is download it for free
sed quia id liberum sit download
it's compatible with your linux machine
quia est compatible cum apparatus Linux
you can get it to go it's gonna be
vos can adepto ut suus 'agnus dei esse
awesome and it allows you to remote into
horribilis et sino vos in remotis
her system very much like log me in on
ratio eius in me log sicut diversi generis multa nimis
Windows but this one works with linux
Sed unus operatur cum Fenestra Linux
and windows and mac and all that kind of
et fenestrae Mac genus
stuff and it's a free download give it a
effercio quod suus 'a free download tribuo is a
go check it out teamviewer.com that's
quod eum ire reprehendo teamviewer.com
the one I was right favorite road okay
ventus rectum iter unam purus
well are there we go we're literally out
Sunt etiam ibi ad litteram de sumus
of time but I know that's going to
Scio suus 'iens, sed temporis
answer your troubles there at least with
respondendum est laborum et certe
regards to the computer issue but I
sed respiciens ad exitus in computatrum
would love to see
amo ut videre
shut up on linux that fantastic how are
Suspendisse ut quomodo clausos Linux
you gonna install you're gonna have to
es agnus dei agnus dei ad install vestri '
go visit the distance 80 miles any money
LXXX passuum intervallo pecuniam ire
telemeters 80 miles or are you okay all
Bene omnia sunt passuum LXXX telemeters
right good luck thanks everybody for
bonus fortuna omnibus gratias agens pro dextro
watching safa dramatis is gonna be here
hic est agnus dei spectant safa dramatis
joining me in the studio next week we're
Studio joining me in altera septimana sumus
the fight sauce Sasha show the grocery
Not pugna condimentum ostendit grocery
store the other day she told me she's
aliam thesaurizate autem ad me die illa
like that this guy's stalking me yeah I
Quod est istud hoc guy amo mihi non yeah
was like I was at the grocery store and
sicut grocery copia, et ego eram in
he was there i was at the cafe he was
Erat autem ibi esset casu
there i was you know she's arab and then
ibi eram et Arabum suus 'non scitis
I was pulling out of the parking lot
Sum trahens de raedam sortem
that doc molds were in playing Friday
doc qui erant in pertusura cribri remanebit Veneris ludo
night and she was walking with a frenzy
nox et cum ambularet poenam vecors
and so she thinks you're stalking her I
et sic cogitat istud tu mihi eam
am yeah I'm sale yeah I am yeah it's
yeah ego sum ego sum yeah yeah sale suus '
true hire folks have a good night we'll
verum fit bonum nocte mercedem dabimus
see ya next week
Puer deinde septimana videbunt
you
vos
we hope you enjoyed the show category 5
Spero fruendum vos autem genus spectaculum V
TV broadcasts live from Barrie Ontario
TV broadcasts live from Barrie Ontario
Canada every tuesday at seven p.m.
Canada factis qualibct die martis post septimam horam post meridiem
eastern if you're watching this on
Si vos es orientem spectans in hac
demand or through cable TV check out the
demanda per funem TV, vel reprehendo sicco
local show times in your area at
loci ad spectaculum area tua tempora,
category 5 TV and find out when you can
et quando TV invenire potes V genus
watch live and interact in the community
vigilate et penitus vivere in civitatem
chat room category 5 is a production of
chat cubiculum quod productio est genus V
prodigy digital solutions and is
et prodigiis digital solutions
licensed under creative commons
licensed under partum plebe
attribution 2.5 canada we'll see you
adscribi autem 2.5 Canada te videre
next time thanks for tuning in
iterum gratias in tuning